# **KENNY KAO**

## · 1050 George Street · New Brunswick, NJ 08901 · (732) 289-8464 ·kennykao1203@gmail.com ·Linkedin.com/in/kennykao PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned IT Specialist with 4-year background in Information Technology. Progressive experience marked by continuous contributions above and beyond requirements. Career achievements in large-scale software deployments, network buildouts, and data security. A current Graduate student pursuing Masters of Business and Science with a concentration in Cybersecurity.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Technical: Microsoft (Active Directory, Skype for Business, MDT, Office 2007-2016, Exchange, Office 365, Windows 7-10, Server 2008-2016), ManageEngine (Desktop Central, ServiceDesk Plus), Ticket Systems (Spiceworks, Micro Focus Service Desk, ServiceNow), Network Administration (Internet, DNS, DHCP, FTP, File & Print Services), File Recovery, Bomgar, Quest KACE K1000, McAfee, Symantec (Endpoint Protection, Veritas Backup Exec 14, GhostCast Suite, DLO), Malwarebytes, Lansweeper, Cisco AnyConnect, Advanced Malware Protection, WebEx, Asset Management, Documentation, HTML, WordPress, SAP, Hyper-V Manager, VMware Workstation, Arkadin, Mitel VoIP telephones, Quantum Backup library, PRTG, Dell ImageAssist, Micro Focus - Novell (iManager, iPrint, Zenworks), Kronos InTouch Time Clocks, macOS, iOS, Android
- Certification: ITIL Foundation, Windows 10 Supporting and Troubleshooting (10982B)
- Language: English, Mandarin Chinese

#### ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Saved company thousands of dollars in budget management by selling used Dell/HP servers and SAN storage arrays
- Configured and implemented Spiceworks Portal and Helpdesk ticketing system
- Aided in global company computer infrastructure by upgrading operating system from Windows 7 to Windows 10
- Managed IT assets and inventory include purchasing from vendors to reduce cost and expenses

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Rutgers University** Piscataway, NJ Unit Computing Specialist July 2017 to Current

- Created a Windows 10 reference image using Microsoft's MDT to be deployed to new computers for the University department
- Assisted with KACE for asset management and bundles for software roll-outs such as Adobe and AutoCAD
- Administer Adobe Creative Cloud purchase and installation for the department

Unit Administrator/Specialist January 2017 to July 2017

- Provided on-campus and off-campus desktop/laptop support to over 1000 end-users (desk-side/dial-in) on a variety of Windows desktop and laptop computers during business hours
- Install Ricoh, HP, Brother printers and configure E-Copy stations across facilities building for users to print, scan, copy and fax
- Work with vendors to get quotes to purchase IT hardware using University's Marketplace
- Enroll new employees to the Kronos Time clock system by biometrics and troubleshoot when malfunction
- Assist in email migration from legacy email client and Exchange to Office 365
- Work closely with the Rutgers Telecommunications Division and Office of Information Technology to troubleshoot central voice and data networks

Sabert Corporation Savreville, NI IT Help Desk Technician August 2015 to January 2017

- Provided on-site and 24/7 off-site desktop support to 300 end-users (desk-side/dial-in) on a variety of Windows desktop and laptop computers
- Performed system administrator tasks include creating new domain account, Exchange mailbox set up, migrating to Office 365, regulate Quantum back up tape library and recovery, PRTG bandwidth monitoring, and handling access card system
- Implemented IT solutions such as robust help desk ticketing system, inventory management, computer imaging, patch management, VNC and 2-step authentication token system
- Assist global Windows 10 deployment by upgrading 100 ineligible hardware and testing best solution for OS software deployment

**Sabert Corporation** Sayreville, NJ IT Intern May 2015 to August 2015

- Supported incoming helpdesk to the Service Desk by telephone and e-mail to ensure timely and effective resolution of end user issues
- Performed hands-on fixes at the helpdesk level, including installing and upgrading software, installing hardware, implementing backup, and configuring systems and applications
- Documented all pertinent end user identification information, wide range of computing problem or issue, and Helpdesk system

## **EDUCATION**

**RUTGERS UNIVERSITY** New Brunswick, NI Masters of Business and Science September 2018 to May 2021

Concentration in Cybersecurity

School of Communication and Information & School of Arts and Science

September 2011 to May 2015

Bachelor of Arts in Information Technology, Minor in Digital Communication, Information, and Media

Cumulative Major GPA: 3.9

Dean's List (Spring 2013, Fall 2013, Fall 2014)